# Yan Xiang

♦ https://yx-hci.github.io/ | ≥ yanxiang@sjtu.edu.cn | ≥ Yan Xiang | 1 +(86)18565304687

# Research Interests

My broad research interests include Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Human-AI Interaction (HAI), and AR & VR, and their application to computer-supported cooperative work, social computing, digital health, as well as data-driven approach to human-centered design and pervasive computing.

# Education

Shanghai Jiao Tong University (SJTU), Shanghai, China Sep. 2021 - Mar. 2024 (Expected) Master of Engineering in International Industrial Design Engineering (English Program), School of Design GPA: 3.92/4.0, Rank: 2/39 (Top 5%), Outstanding Graduate Scholarship (Top 0.5%)

Northeastern University (NEU), Shenyang, China Bachelor of Engineering in Architecture, School of Architecture GPA: 88.20/100, Rank: 3/66 (Top 5%), Provincial Outstanding Graduate (Top 1%)

Singapore University of Technology and Design (SUTD), Singapore Sep. 2023 - Jan. 2024 Visiting Student, Data-Driven Innovation Lab, Engineering Product Development Pillar

Seoul National University (SNU), Seoul, South Korea Sep. 2018 - Jun. 2019 Exchange Student, Architecture, Department of Architecture & Architectural Engineering GPA: 3.83/4.3 (94.30/100)

Bauhaus-Universität Weimar, Weimar, Germany Summer Institute, Architecture and Urbanism

Jun. 2019 - Aug. 2019

Sep. 2016 - Jun. 2021

## **Publications**

ISTE '22	Xiang, Y., Chang, D., Yao, Y., Wang, L., et al. (2022). "Usability Evaluation of Elder-
	Friendly Design: Application to Take Alipay App." In Transdisciplinarity and the Future
	of Engineering (pp. 154-163), IOS Press. https://doi.org/10.3233/ATDE220642.
DIS '23	Xiang, Y., Fan, Q., Qian, K., Li. J., et al. (2023). "Decentralized Governance for Virtual

DIS '23 Xiang, Y., Fan, Q., Qian, K., Li. J., et al. (2023). "Decentralized Governance for Virtual WiP Community (DeGov4VC): Optimal Policy Design of Human-plant Symbiosis Co-creation." In DIS'23 Companion: Companion Publication of the 2023 ACM Designing Interactive Systems Conference (pp.207-212). https://doi.org/10.1145/3563703.3596621.

Chang, D., Xiang, Y., Zhao, J., Qian, Y., & Li, F. (2022). "Exploration of Brain-Computer Interaction for Supporting Children's Attention Training: A Multimodal Design Based on Attention Network and Gamification Design.", International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 19(22), 15046. (SCI, JCR Q1, First student author). https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph192215046.

IEEM '23 Xiang, Y., Chang, D., Feng, X. (2023). "Leveraging Urban Big Data for Informed Business Location Decisions: A Case Study of Starbucks in Tianhe District, Guangzhou City.", In 2023 IEEE International Conference on Industrial Engineering and Engineering Management (IEEM), IEEE. (Accepted). http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.09778.

Xiang, Y., Chang, D., Cheng, J. (2023). "Exploring the Correlation between Urban Microclimate Simulation and Urban Morphology: A Case Study in Yeongdeungpo-gu, Seoul.", In 2023 IEEE International Conference on Industrial Engineering and Engineering Management (IEEM), IEEE (Accepted). http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.09779.

Comput Xiang, Y., Zhang, Z., Chang, D., Tu, L. (2023). "The Impact of Gamified Auditory-Verbal Training for Hearing-Challenged Children at Intermediate and Advanced Rehabilitation Stages." Computers & Education. (SCI, Under Review). http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.11047.

- CHI '24 Zhang, J.\*, Xiang, Y.\*, Zhao, Y.\*, Jin, X., ... & LC, R. (2024). "From Design Inspiration to Co-curation: The Changing Role of Curatorial Practice in a Digital Generative AI Landscape for the Arts.", In 2024 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. (Under Review, \*Co-first Authors).
- HRI '24 Xiang, Y. (2024). "A System Design for Multi-Modal Emotion Regulation and Management in Human-Robot and Human-Computer Interactions." In 2024 19th ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction. (Under Review).
- IMWUT '24 Zhou, C., Ram, A., Gu, Y., ... & Xiang, Y. (2024). "GlassMail: Towards Personalised Wearable Assistant for On-the-go Email Creation on Smart Glasses." *Proceedings of the ACM on Interactive, Mobile, Wearable and Ubiquitous Technologies.* (Submitted).
- Preprint Chang, D., Xiang, Y.\*, Zhu, X. (2023). "A Style Matching Approach for the Generative Design of Animated Posters." (Preprint, \*Co-first authors and corresponding author).

# Research Experience

#### Information and Interaction Lab @ School of Design, SJTU

Research Assistant, Advisor: Prof. Danni Chang, Prof. Zhenyu Gu

Sept. 2021 - Present

# Gamified Brain-Computer Interaction in Children's Attention Training [More Details]

- Developed a multimodal BCI gamification attention training system through real-time EEG command.
- Independently completed the design and development of training game with Unity based on C#.
- Verified by the experiment (p<0.05), the system significantly improves the users' attention behaviors.

#### Usability Evaluation and Strategy for Elder-Friendly Design [More Details]

- Applied the elder-friendly mode to tackle the accessibility and the usability problem through experiment.
- Analyzed eye movement data, derived design strategies through information architecture, task flow and UI.
- Accepted by the ISTE '23 Conference, orally presented in MIT, Cambridge, USA.

## Gamefied Auditory-verbal Training System Design for Children [More Details]

- Designed gamefied training system for children in intermediate and advanced hearing rehabilitation stage.
- Utilized voice and facial mouth shape recognition technology in developing the training system.
- Enhanced the auditory speech rehabilitation training in improving language abilities (n=31, p<0.05).

#### Style Matching Approach for Generative Design of Animated Posters [More Details]

- Applied Kansei Engineering to create a dynamic style labeling dataset by generating and labeling samples.
- Trained a BP neural network and combined genetic algorithm for animated style-matching model.
- Conducted comparative experiments, validated the parametric generation model's validity and usability (p<0.05).

#### Master's Thesis: Multimodal Emotion System via Brain-Computer Interaction [More Details]

- Developed a multimodal emotion recognition and regulation service system for space through AIGC.
- Designed a real-time adjustment model based on brain-computer interaction through EEG signal.
- Verified the effectiveness by conducting experiment with participants in Shanghai Mental Health Center.

#### MIT Media Lab-City Science Lab @ Shanghai

Research Assistant, Advisor: Dr. Yan Zhang (Ryan), Prof. Kent Larson

Sept. 2021 - Aug. 2023

#### Human-AI Co-creation System Design for Decentralized VR Community [More Details]

- Proposed a decentralized governance model for a virtual community and designed an optimal symbiosis policy.
- Developed a co-creation DAO and evaluated co-design impact through AI agent-based simulation.
- Co-organized the MIT City Science Submit & SocityDAO workshop as one of the main mentors (1/10).
- Accepted by the DIS '23 Conference as work in progress paper as the first author.

#### NUS-HCI Lab, Department of Computer Science @ National University of Singapore

Research Assistant, Advisor: Prof. Shengdong (Shen) Zhao

May 2023 - Oct. 2023

#### Enhancing Empathetic Interaction through Heads-up Computing by AR Glasses

• Investigated how multimodal modes of emotional messages impact users' perception through AR glasses.

- Proposed effective co-creation methods and tool for empathic communication through AIGC technique.
- Validated that the proposed system facilitates deeper emotional interaction experiences.
- Submitted to IMWUT '24 Conference.

#### Data-Driven Innovation Lab @ Singapore University of Technology and Design

Visiting Student, Advisor: Prof. Jianxi Luo

Sept. 2023 - Jan. 2024 (Expected)

# Chatbot as an Advisor for Designer via Using Large Language Models (LLMs)

- Developed a system and framework through prompt-based learning using the GPT-4 and DALL-E API
- Designed and developed an empathetic chatbot for engaging user interactions and visualize user status.
- Utilized language inference techniques to generate and enhance users' knowledge systems within the design.

# Brain Computer Interface Lab @ Rui Jin Hospital Clinical Neuroscience Center & miHoYo

Research Assistant, Advisor: Dr. Odin van der Stelt, Prof. Baoliang LU

Oct. 2022 - Present

#### Investigating Digital Therapeutics and Designing PD-CAT for Parkinson's Disease

- Conducted research on digital health products for elderly and designed experimental paradigms.
- Developed a Parkinson's disease cognitive assessment and training tool on mobile and wearable devices.
- Experimentally verified significant improvement in cognitive clinical patient behavior (p<0.05).

# Pervasive Human Computer Interaction Lab @ Tsinghua University

Summer Research, Advisor: Prof. Xin Yi, Prof. Yuntao Wang, Prof. Yuanchun Shi May 2023- Sep. 2023

# Facilitating Interaction with AIGC Using Proactive Feedback

- Investigated how users perceive and respond to empathetic and unconventional expressions from AI agents.
- Developed proactive feedback mechanism through 8 personality utilizing prompt engineering technology.
- Contrasted experiments on arousal and valence dimensions, revealing improved user emotional engagement.

## HCI-X Summer Research @ CityU & DKU & HKUST(GZ)

Summer Research, Advisor: Prof. Ray LC, Prof. Xin Tong, Prof. Mingming Fan June 2023 - Sep. 2023

#### Exploring Human-AI Co-creation Approach in Digital Space and VR Exhibitions [More Details]

- Interviewed and encoded curators' insights into how the AIGC tool affects the digital curation experience.
- Created a toolkit enabling curators to employ AI tools in different Human-AI co-curation processes.
- Validated the proposed toolkit through experiments and hosted an open virtual exhibition online.
- Submitted to CHI '24 Conference as the co-first author.

# Teaching Assistantship

User Study international course (taught in English), SJTU, Shanghai, China

Sep. 2022 - Jan.2023

- Conducted instruction classes on data analysis using SPSS and MATLAB to quantitative research in user study.
- Evaluated weekly assignments and provided guidance for 38 domestic and international graduate students.

# Leadership & Innovation

• Delegate, Shape Machine Symposium @Georgia Tech & SNU, Seoul, South Korea	July 2019
• Exhibitor, "Third Space", exhibited in the Seoul Biennale of Architecture and Urbanism	Nov. 2019
• Delegate, ICDF Conference, China-Italy Design Innovation Hub, Tsinghua University	Nov. 2021
• Representative, Roundtable Talk, WDO World Industrial Design Day	June 2022
• Oral speaker, ISTE Conference, MIT Wong Auditorium, Cambridge, MA, USA	July 2022
• Delegate, Brain-Computer Interface & Neurotechnology Spring School, IEEE Brain	Apr. 2023
• Independent Exhibitor, "Twisting", exhibited in World Expo Museum, Shanghai	Nov. 2022
• Founder, "Neuro-Emotive", Invested by Prof. Zexiang LI (Former Chair of DJI)	May 2023 - Present

# Skills

- Language: English (proficient), Cantonese (proficient), Mandarin Chinese (native)
- Experimental skills: Eye-tracking, and EEG-based brain-computer interface in data processing
- Professional skills: Python, Unity, Unreal Engine, C#, React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MATLAB, SPSS, R